# **Dhana Angdembey**

# Senior Programmer Analyst

Cypress, CA - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Dhana-Angdembey/640c035a14773015

Oracle Certified Professional with over 25 years of experience as a programmer, analyst, and developer using multiple platforms with extensive knowledge of the software development life cycle.

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

WORK EXPERIENCE

#### **Programmer Analyst**

Care1st Health Plan - Park, KS - May 2016 to Present

Oracle PISql, SSIS, SSRS, C#, Visual Studio, ETL & report etc

#### **Senior Programmer Analyst**

HMS Inc - Alhambra, CA - May 2007 to December 2015

Design and development of data warehouse for Angeles County Los Managed Care Services using oracle10g, oracle11g, PLSQL Developer, SQL, SQL\*Loader, SQLPLUS, PLSQL, and Unix shell scripts to process over 50 data sources including data modeling to design database for data warehouse and data marts, development, maintenance and support of Data Warehouse, Data Marts and Data store, automation of daily data loads and processing using UNIX Shell scripting, and design and development of specifications and processes for data loads and user reports using the back-end processing modules developed with SQL, PL/SQL, packages, Unix shell scripts. Design, development and maintenance of automation processes for database replication using regular and prebuilt materialized views, tuning and optimization of queries and stored procedures. Creating, testing, debugging, troubleshooting and maintaining Unix shell scripts and oracle packages, tables, indexes, functions, triggers, and complex queries using dynamic SQL and bulk collect features for performance tuning. Use explain plan and optimizer hints, and gather tables and indexes statistics for performance tuning of SQL queries and processes.

#### Senior Programmer Analyst (Consultant)

Cedars Sinai Medical Center - Los Angeles, CA - January 2007 to April 2007

Design, development and testing Data Warehouse remediation project using Oracle PL/SQL, SQL, SQL\*Loader, SQLPLUS for including Data Warehousing Cedars Sinai Medical Center, Los Angeles Census Data mart project and Clinical Data Repository assessment project. Maintenance, Troubleshooting, testing and debugging for performance tuning of Information System Mart (ISM) reports. Creating, testing, debugging, troubleshooting and maintaining oracle tables, indexes, packages, functions, triggers, and complex queries using dynamic SQL and bulk collect features for performance tuning. Use explain plan and optimizer hints, and gather tables and indexes statistics for performance tuning of SQL queries and processes.

# **Oracle Developer**

University of South Florida SunGard SCT Banner - Tampa, FL - October 2005 to November 2006

7 upgrade project using on

Oracle9i Forms and Reports, PLSQL, SQLPLUS, Pro\*C, also develop, test, and troubleshoot AppWorx chains and modules. Development, troubleshooting and maintenance of Oracle Forms and Report modules of SCT banner upgrade project, and analysis, development, troubleshooting, testing and debugging of backend processing modules including packages, and procedures using

proc\*c and embedded sql. Use explain plan and optimizer hints, and gather tables and indexes statistics for performance tuning of sql queries and processes.

#### **Computer Programmer**

Rastriya Banijya Bank - Kathmandu - November 1994 to December 2004

Transformation of manual banking system into automated banking system in Rastriya Banijya Bank, state owned largest commercial bank in Nepal including Analysis, design, develop,

implement, manage, maintain and support client server banking applications including Data modeling to design databases and business applications, development, support and maintenance, and database management and administration of banking automation systems.

## Part time faculty for teaching

Kathmandu Campus - October 2003 to March 2004

Teaching Database Management System (DBMS) to the class of Bachelors of Computer Application (BCA)

## **Software Developer**

IDI Inc. Offshore Project - Bridgetown - January 1996 to May 1996

Development, testing and debugging of Business Application program using Delphi, Paradox, Windows NT, SQL Server, MS-Office, Report Smith, Object Pascal

# **Computer Consultant**

UNICEF Country Office - Kathmandu - 1995 to March 1996

Worked as developer and DBA to create and process research database in UNICEF Country Office, Kathmandu office in short term projects on Health Operations Research and EPI.

# **Application Programmer**

ANNA Casino - Kathmandu - July 1995 to December 1995

analyses, design develop project called Video Machine Performance System in Annapurna Casino, Kathmandu Nepal

## **Computer Programmer**

Data Systems International - Kathmandu - August 1988 to February 1993

Involved as computer programmer in entire phases of Software development life cycle including analysis, design, development, testing & debugging, deployment, maintenance, and support of various Business Application programs using COBOL and Oracle

# **Computer Programmer**

IDI Inc, Offshore Project - Dayton, OH - June 1990 to March 1991

Involved as software developer in offshore software development and maintenance projects called Product Performance subSystem (PPS), and Deployable Combat Aircraft Maintainable System (DCAMS) for USAF Dayton Ohio USA in Litton Computer System using Oracle and COBOL

#### **EDUCATION**

#### Master of Science in Computer Science

Maharishi University of Management - Fairfield, IA February 2009

# **CERTIFICATIONS/LICENSES**

# **Oracle Certified Professional, Developer**

# ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

#### SKILLS:

Languages: C, C++, C#, ProC, Clipper, Cobol(MS & Realia), Coldfusion, Delphi/Object

HTML, Java, J2EE, JSP, JavaScript, JScript, Korn Shell, Pascal, Paradox,

PL/SQL, Struts, VB .Net, VBScript, Visual Basic, XML, XQuery

Databases: Oracle9i, Oracle10g, Oracle11g, Microsoft SQL Server

Tools: PL/SQL Developer, TOAD, Harvest Enterprise, AppWorx 5.1 (background

process management), Clipper, Rational Rose, Cold Fusion, Eclipse,

ERWin(Data modeling tool), System Designer, SQLPLUS, SQL Developer

Platforms UNIX, LINUX, Sun Solaris, Microsoft Windows

Software: Access, Paradox, MS Office, dBase, FoxPro, Microsoft Project, Report Smith,

Visio

Other: SunGard SCT Banner